in this problem
we are given a local variable alphabet
that references a string and we're asked
to split the value of alphabet by
individual characters
and print each character
we're going to split the string into an
array of characters
let's hop over to irb
and i'm going to paste in that same
variable
alphabet referencing a string
we can use the string split method
to split a string and we'll pass in as
an
argument the character on which we want
to split the string
in this example let's say we want to
split the given string on the character
m
so we'll pass m in as an argument
and you can see that the return value is
an array
in this particular case it's an array of
two elements
because m was present only once in our
given string
our string was split into two
another method ruby provides that allows
us to split a string into an array of
characters
is the chars method it returns an array
of each character in that string
so let's go back and look at our code
[Music]
we'll call the split method on alphabet
you may be wondering what character we
need to pass in
as an argument to split in order to
return an array in which each element
is an individual character we can pass
an empty string into the split method as
an argument
and ruby will split the calling string
into an array of characters
we're going to output the returned array
by passing it to put us
now in the example output we saw that
each character
or each element of this array of
characters
was output on its own line
when we pass an array as an argument to
put s
it outputs each element of that array
on its own line so let's run
our code and see this
our output matches the example output
so we've successfully split our alphabet
string
into an array of characters and printed
each element of that array on its own
line